Humanity will face the dark side of the Moon.
Moonfall is a science fiction, adventure, action
film directed by Roland Emmerich.
A mysterious force knocks the moon from its orbit around Earth and sends
it hurtling on a collision course with life as we know it.
Jocinda Fowler, played by Halle Berry.
Brian Harper, played by Patrick Wilson.
KC Houseman, played by John Bradley.
Sonny Harper, played by Charlie Plummer.
Michelle, played by Kelly Yu.
Tom Lopez, played by Michael Peña.
Moonfall is a 2022 science fiction disaster film co-written,
directed, and produced by Roland Emmerich.
It stars Halle Berry, Patrick Wilson, John Bradley, Michael Peña, Charlie
Plummer, Kelly Yu, Carolina Bartczak, and Donald Sutherland.
It follows two former astronauts alongside a conspiracy theorist who discover the
hidden truth about the Moon when it suddenly leaves its orbit.
Shot in Montreal on a $138–146 million budget, it is one of the most
expensive independently produced films ever made.
The film was theatrically released in North America and the UK on February 4,
2022, by Lionsgate and Entertainment Film Distributors respectively.
It received mixed reviews from critics and was a box office failure,
grossing $67 million worldwide on the budget of $150 million.
The film explores themes of moon, looting, space
travel, flooding, lost civilisation.
The tone is thought_provoking.